Moving to a new country is exciting—until you need
to understand how everything actually works.
You have an address in the Netherlands.
But what comes next—and where do you even start?
YouNew turns that uncertainty into a simple sequence:
first, register with the municipality and receive a BSN.
Then use it to set up DigiD.
After that, check Dutch health insurance.
One question becomes clear next steps,
in the right order.
When a step needs more detail, the guide explains
what it means, what to prepare, and where to verify it.
Official sources stay visible, so the user can continue
with the responsible Dutch institution—not another anonymous blog.
YouNew does not replace government advice.
It helps a newcomer understand where to begin and what to do next.
And life is bigger than one checklist.
A newcomer may need a nearby service
or information for a specific city…
…or help finding healthcare, housing,
work, and legal resources.
Map, search, cities, and categories keep those needs connected
in one place—without turning the first weeks into twenty open tabs.
YouNew started as a simple idea:
make the first months in a new country less confusing.
I wasn't a professional software engineer.
ChatGPT helped me shape the product and its story.
Codex helped me build, stabilize, and prepare the iOS app.
They expanded what I could create, while the vision and decisions stayed mine.
This is YouNew—
a clearer first step in the Netherlands.